<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization_project_02</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv2/proxmoxv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv2/proxmoxv2/</guid>
      <description>The elephant in the room: I feel it is important to say that this post has been a LONG time coming. I have not properly updated anything on this site in over 2 years! School took up too much of my time to document the projects that I did along the way, but rest assured things still happened!
Proxmox post again? Yes, I finally succeeded in seting up Proxmox for my homelab.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-elephant-in-the-room&#34;&gt;The elephant in the room:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel it is important to say that this post has been a LONG time coming. I have not properly updated anything on this site in over 2 years!
School took up too much of my time to document the projects that I did along the way, but rest assured things still happened!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proxmox-post-again&#34;&gt;Proxmox post again?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I finally succeeded in seting up Proxmox for my homelab. Here is a list of things that have contributed to this success:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My College&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range switched from OpenStack to a more manageable Proxmox thanks to the work of Karl Trowbridge and myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned that you can do a custom installation of proxmox over Debian 12.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My understanding of virtualization as a whole increased substantially.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proxmox updates have improved functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-project-idea&#34;&gt;Updated Project Idea:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve homelab with a virtualization server to isolate and control all the services I run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;constraints&#34;&gt;Constraints:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many different issues that make my needs very different than a standard Proxmox installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I needed it to be networked over WiFi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to be able to handle the networking through Software Defined Networking only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the second issue has been fixed in recent versions of Proxmox to be much easier to acomplish, the first is still a rather complicated issue to resolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps-taken&#34;&gt;Steps taken:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As crazy as it may sound, you need to install Proxmox from a Debian base&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is to ensure that you can install network manager to get wifi with nmtui.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow this guide: (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Install_Proxmox_VE_on_Debian_12_Bookworm&#34;&gt;https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Install_Proxmox_VE_on_Debian_12_Bookworm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From there it is a fairly simple setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you are running proxmox 8.1+ you can set up a virtual internal NAT based network through SDN settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up an SDN with the type simple&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure it allows for SNAT when making it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a purely simplistic sense that is all! wow! you now have SNAT networking in your Proxmox wifi version!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there are a few things that need to be run each startup for this to work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allow ipv4 forwarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any port forwarding rules that you wish to run need to be set through IPTables rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the problems in the networking requiring IPTables rules to be run at startup, I wrote a simple SystemD service to run these commands at boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record since it took me a long time to find the command for opening up a NAT&amp;rsquo;d service to the local network, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ iptables -t nat -I PREROUTING -p {tcp or udp} -d {your host IP on network} --dport {port for local network} -j DNAT --to-destination {VMIP:VMPort}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization_project_01</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/proxmoxv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/proxmoxv1/</guid>
      <description>Project Idea: I would like to have a system for network virtualization service for my own personal projects and homelab.
Investigation stage The initial idea for this project was inspired by my school&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range (which is currently maintained by yours truly). I really like how in the Cyber Range students can get a virtual machine hosted over the network to allow for a sandboxed environment that is ofloaded to a separate machine.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-idea&#34;&gt;Project Idea:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to have a system for network virtualization service for my own personal projects and homelab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigation-stage&#34;&gt;Investigation stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial idea for this project was inspired by my school&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range (which is currently maintained by yours truly). I really like how in the Cyber Range students can get a virtual machine hosted over the network to allow for a sandboxed environment that is ofloaded to a separate machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range runs on Openstack which is a really nice project, but it is a bit overly complicated for my needs in a personal project such as this. So I went to work and investigated the following systems to handle this for me while trying to find the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openstack (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstack.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.openstack.org/&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a little bit too complex for my needs, but if I had more servers and time it would be fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ESXi by VMWare (&lt;a href=&#34;https://core.vmware.com/esxi&#34;&gt;https://core.vmware.com/esxi&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is far too expensive for me if I were to use the official version as it is enterprise and has enterprise level licenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proxmox
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source and extremely simple setup in comparison to all others. It does require a very particular network setup especially over wifi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux with KVM and SPICE
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really nice and would be the most simple for me. Setting up new vms is a pain and manual networking of vms is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-decision&#34;&gt;My Decision:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go with Proxmox as at this point in time it makes the most sense for me to use it. Its free version is very appealing and it has a decently easy installer with easy to manage vms and vm networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-download-and-prepare&#34;&gt;Step 1: Download and prepare&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to proxmox&amp;rsquo;s website and specifically their download page (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proxmox.com/en/downloads/category/iso-images-pve)&#34;&gt;https://www.proxmox.com/en/downloads/category/iso-images-pve)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I used the usb flasher tool rufus (&lt;a href=&#34;https://rufus.ie/en/&#34;&gt;https://rufus.ie/en/&lt;/a&gt;) to flash a spare usb drive with the iso.
For my specific setup, I needed the following settings in rufus to get it to work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure it is in uefi mode not mbr or legacy or bios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to flash it in DD mode when prompted because my laptop where I would be installing it did not like ISO mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than a few issues with the Dell bios, once I had booted into the Proxmox Installer, the installation was very straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the installer took me to the license Agreement page:
&lt;img alt=&#34;eula.jpg&#34; src=&#34;https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/eula.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you had to select your disk where you wanted it installed:
&lt;img alt=&#34;disk_Select&#34; src=&#34;https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/driveSelect.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there it was simple setup stuff like setting time zone and email address for management:
&lt;img alt=&#34;time_Zone&#34; src=&#34;https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/timeZone.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;email/password&#34; src=&#34;https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/password.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was here that I have hit my main issue with the project so far. You see, I am on a network at my college that I can not control and where I am discouraged from running such servers as this. For this reason, I am working on making a little (and quite slow) network using an esp32 module on a little arduino. I know this will not supply me with great speeds or even reliability, but given my current circumstance, I would say it is a win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That part of the project is what I am currently working on, so stay tuned for me to finish this project if you want to see how I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats all for now!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers Test of bold font.
As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.
I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers &lt;strong&gt;Test of bold font&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont. Some things that came to mind are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is open source which is awesome and allows me to do a bit more tweaking than most services would allow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface is simple enough and can be done via the comand line if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The themes make for quick and easy start of this project which was heavily desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It allowed for easy offloading to github sites which would allow me to have a free host. (I am in college so money is a bit hard to come by sometimes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This added money allows me to save up to get a domain name!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned to this site to stay up to date on my escapades into computer maddness as I occasionally ask the questions we all want to hear like, &amp;ldquo;why not?&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;can this run Linux?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
