<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virtualizatio_project_01</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/proxmoxv1/</guid>
      <description>Project Idea: I would like to have a system for network virtualization service for my own persoal projects and homelab like setup.
Investigation stage The initial idea for this project was inspired by my shcool&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range (which is currently maintained by yours truly). I really like how in the Cyber Range students can get a virtual machine hosted over the network to allow for a sandboxed environment that is ofloaded to a separate machine.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-idea&#34;&gt;Project Idea:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to have a system for network virtualization service for my own persoal projects and homelab like setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigation-stage&#34;&gt;Investigation stage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial idea for this project was inspired by my shcool&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range (which is currently maintained by yours truly). I really like how in the Cyber Range students can get a virtual machine hosted over the network to allow for a sandboxed environment that is ofloaded to a separate machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Range runs on Openstack which is a really nice project, but it is a bit overly complicated for my needs in a personal project such as this. So I went to work and investigated the following systems to handle this for me while trying to find the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openstack (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstack.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.openstack.org/&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a little bit too complex for my needs, but if I had more servers and time it would be fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ESXi by VMWare (&lt;a href=&#34;https://core.vmware.com/esxi&#34;&gt;https://core.vmware.com/esxi&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is far too expensive for me if I were to use the official version as it is enterprise and has enterprise level licenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proxmox
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source and extremely simple setup in comparison to all others. It does require a very particular network setup especially over wifi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux with KVM and SPICE
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really nice and would be the most simple for me. Setting up new vms is a pain and manual networking of vms is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-decision&#34;&gt;My Decision:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go with Proxmox as at this point in time it makes the most sense for me to use it. Its free version is very appealing and it has a decently easy installer with easy to manage vms and vm networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-download-and-prepare&#34;&gt;Step 1: Download and prepare&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to proxmox&amp;rsquo;s website and specifically their download page (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proxmox.com/en/downloads/category/iso-images-pve)&#34;&gt;https://www.proxmox.com/en/downloads/category/iso-images-pve)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I used the usb flasher tool rufus () to flash a spare usb drive with the iso.
For my specific setup, I needed the following settings in rufus to get it to work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure it is in uefi mode not mbr or legacy or bios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to flash it in DD mode when prompted because my laptop where I would be installing it did not like ISO mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than a few issues with the Dell bios, once I had booted into the Proxmox Installer, the installation was very straight forward.
In the future, I will come back to this part of my site and add pictures I took of the installation process and annotate them. I just need to figure out how to accomplish that with this website builder first and I wanted to get a little bit of this project out before I got carried away with other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers Test of bold font.
 As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.
 I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers &lt;strong&gt;Test of bold font&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont. Some things that came to mind are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is open source which is awesome and allows me to do a bit more tweaking than most services would allow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface is simple enough and can be done via the comand line if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The themes make for quick and easy start of this project which was heavily desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It allowed for easy offloading to github sites which would allow me to have a free host. (I am in college so money is a bit hard to come by sometimes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This added money allows me to save up to get a domain name!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned to this site to stay up to date on my escapades into computer maddness as I occasionally ask the questions we all want to hear like, &amp;ldquo;why not?&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;can this run Linux?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
