<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jett&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missionfriend1.github.io/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers Test of bold font.
 As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.
 I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello readers! This is my first real post on this blog. I want to set up this blog to hopefully keep track of some of my projects that I work on for my journey learning computers &lt;strong&gt;Test of bold font&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I am using this post to check out a couple of the features that this particular website builder has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to go with the website builder called Hugo for my website building that is because it offered me a couple of things that most modern website builders dont. Some things that came to mind are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is open source which is awesome and allows me to do a bit more tweaking than most services would allow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface is simple enough and can be done via the comand line if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The themes make for quick and easy start of this project which was heavily desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It allowed for easy offloading to github sites which would allow me to have a free host. (I am in college so money is a bit hard to come by sometimes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This added money allows me to save up to get a domain name!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned to this site to stay up to date on my escapades into computer maddness as I occasionally ask the questions we all want to hear like, &amp;ldquo;why not?&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;can this run Linux?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
